Vahan Nanumyan Dr. sc. ETH Zurich

+41 78 715 72 64 vahan@nanumyan.com Zurich, Switzerland www.sa.ethz.ch/people/vnanumvan GitHub:// nanumyan LinkedIn:// nanumvan

Post-doctoral data science researcher at ETH Zurich. Experienced in teaching large classes and in directly supervising students. Skilled in random graphs, large-scale data analysis, statistics & machine learning, data visualisation.



updated on 17th January 2019

EDUCATION

ETH ZURICH

DOCTOR OF SCIENCES May 2018 | Zurich, Switzerland thesis: Structure and Dynamics of Collaborative Knowledge Networks

ETH ZURICH

MSc in Physics May 2014 | Zurich, Switzerland thesis: Master Equations for Heterogeneous Evolution of Interdependent Networks graded 6.0 / 6.0

YEREVAN STATE UNIVERSITY

BSc in Physics May 2010 | Yerevan, Armenia thesis: Light waves in 1D photonic

crystals with arbitrarily changing dielectric and magnetic permittivities GPA: 4.0 / 4.0, honours

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

English Fluent German Beginner Native Armenian Russian Native equal

ANALYTICAL

Graphs and Network Theory Multivariate Statistics Machine Learning Social Network Analysis

PROGRAMMING

Over 5000 lines: Python • R • LATEX Over 1000 lines: SQL • Neo4j Cypher HTML · CSS · Mathematica Familiar: Javascript • Bash • C • PHP • Matlab

VISUALISATION

Data:

D3.js · Matplotlib · ggplot2 · Gephi Illustration:

Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator • Inkscape • GIMP 3D Graphics and CAD:

Blender • AutoCAD • 3ds Max

EXPERIENCE

ETH ZURICH - CHAIR OF SYSTEMS DESIGN | RESEARCHER & LECTURER

Jan 2013 - Present | Zurich, Switzerland

- As a PostDoc and previously a Doctoral candidate, developing new statistical methods for large and complex networked systems and applying these to real-world problems, e.g., for identifying fraudulent behaviour in socio-technical systems.
- Supervised 6 MSc student projects, teaching Systems Dynamics & Complexity (150 students), Agent-Based Modelling and Complex Networks together with Prof. Frank Schweitzer
- System administration for the group including maintenance of Linux servers, a small computing cluster and about 15 user laptops

DINAMICA TESTING CENTRE | FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Feb 2011 - Sep 2011 | Yerevan, Armenia

 Designed and coded multiple small websites for WordPress and proprietary **CMS**

ANDAVA DIGITAL MARKETING AGENCY | SEO SPECIALIST

Jan 2010 – Jan 2011 I Yerevan, Armenia

• SEO for the websites of a Moscow-based travel company by means of code & content optimisation and growth of incoming links from bloggers

EUROSTAN-UYUT | TECHNICAL DRAWING & 3D VISUALISATION

Jan 2004 - Dec 2009 | Yerevan, Armenia

- Intermediary between company engineers and customers in construction
- Provided CAD technical drawings to engineers and 3D visualisation for the customers

AWARDS

2011-2014 Scholarship for MSc studies, Luys Foundation Best MSc student in IT presidential award, Armenia 2011 Best BSc student in IT presidential award, Armenia 2009 2006–2010 Excellence scholarship, Yerevan State University

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS & WORKING PAPERS

- · Nanumyan, V., Friend-or-Foe? Normalized Deviations in Discrete Asymmetric Distributions, working paper
- · Nanumyan, V., Schweitzer, F., Modelling Coupled Growth of Multilayer Networks, working paper
- · Casiraghi, G., Nanumyan, V., Generalized Hypergeometric Ensembles of Random Graphs: the Configuration Model as an Urn Problem. arXiv:1810.06495, submitted to SIAM J. Appl. Math.
- · Schweitzer, F., Nanumyan, V., A conceptual approach to model co-evolution of urban structures, International Journal of Space Structures (2016): 31(1), pp43-51.
- Schweitzer, F., Nanumyan, V., Tessone, C. J., Xia, X., How Do OSS Projects Change In Number And Size? A Large-Scale Analysis To Test A Model Of Project Growth, Advances in Complex Systems (2015): 1550008.
- Nanumyan, V., Garas, A., Schweitzer, F., The Network of Counterparty Risk: Analysing Correlations in OTC Derivatives, PLoS ONE 10(9) (2015): e0136638.